Guide to the Washington Office on Africa Records - Addendum A
Yale University Divinity School Library
Washington Office on Africa Records - Addendum A
1966-1999
RG 105A
Yale University Divinity School Library
30
(61 boxes)
This collection is an addendum to the publications, correspondence, reports, statements, and collected material documenting the work of the Washington Office on Africa found in Record Group 105. The Washington Office on Africa was founded in 1972 to support the movement for freedom from white-minority rule in southern Africa. Its activities have included the monitoring of Congressional legislation and executive policies and actions, as well as the publication of action alerts and other documentation designed to advance progressive legislation and policy on southern Africa. Supported by church bodies and unions, the WOA has worked in partnership with colleagues in Africa, the Africa advocacy community in the United States, and grassroots organizations concerned with various aspects of African affairs.
Washington Office on Africa
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Washington Office on Africa.
Biographical / Historical
See the finding aid for Record Group 105.
Scope and Contents
The organization of the materials in this collection is an improvement over the chaotic state in which they were received, but is quite minimal. Series I, Office files / correspondence/ meetings, contains material dating from 1982 to 1996. The sub-series with Series I reflect apparent subsections within the WOA's files: WOA Tenth Anniversary Celebration; Miscellaneous events, projects; Chronological Files; Email Records. Series II, Country files, is arranged in alphabetical order by name of country. Series III, Topical, includes the following sub-series: Religious; NGOs, Trade, Advocacy Work and Topical Files, Files on Individual Representatives and Senators.
Arrangement
I. Office files / Correspondence / Meetings
II. Country Files
III. Topical Files
Anti-apartheid movements -- United States; Apartheid -- South Africa; Church and state -- United States; Disinvestment; Lobbying -- Law and legislation -- United States; Angola -- Politics and government; Mozambique -- Politics and government; Namibia -- Politics and government; South Africa -- Politics and government -- 1978-1989; United States -- Foreign relations -- South Africa; Zimbabwe -- Politics and government; Washington Office on Africa
- Office Files / Correspondence / Meetings, Series I
  - WOA Tenth Anniversary Celebration
    - Committee members - lists, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Program and invitations, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Program, celebration, publicity, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Committee members - meeting minutes, agendas, etc, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Invitation lists, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Honorary sponsors lists, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters to honorary sponsors, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Paying sponsors- letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Organizing, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - WOA Tenth Anniversary Celebration, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Honorary sponsors-responses, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Honorary sponsors-coupons, misc, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Paying sponsors coupons, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Follow-up thank you letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Paying sponsors -responses, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Paying sponsors lists, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous events, projects
    - Resources I, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Info on 1st and 2nd Annual MLK Jr. Symposium on Southern Africa, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    - Folder entitled "Imani Countess" containing miscellaneous documents (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Nelson Mandela Reception Rally, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Press Work, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Info on Southern Africa, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - South African Women 's advocacy training project, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
    - Angola Current Work Folder, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Legislation: Angola, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30-34)
    - Misc. Projects completed, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
    - Africa Peace Tour, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    - Reception Committee, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Info on Chris Hani and apartheid South Africa, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - SAWG meeting, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
    - ACOA Board meeting, Dec 1992 (Box 4, Folder 43-44)
    - USFP Conference presenter correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - NCC/WOA meeting notes, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - CWS Strategy Sessions, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 47-50)
    - WOA/ APIC 1996 Program Files Africa Round Table (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Advocacy Kit Originals, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 52-54)
    - Speaking Engagements-Vicki, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Chronological Files
    - Chronological File, 1992 Jul-Sep (Box 5, Folder 56-63)
    - Chronological File, 1992 Oct-993 Feb 24 (Box 6, Folder 64-77)
    - Chronological File, 1993 Feb 24-May 11 (Box 7, Folder 78-87)
    - Chronological File, 1993 May 1-11 (Box 8, Folder 88-89)
    - Chronological File, 1993 May 13-Jun (Box 8, Folder 90-95)
    - Chronological File, 1993 Jun-Aug (Box 9, Folder 96-104)
    - Chronological File, 1993 Sep-Oct (Box 10, Folder 105-109)
  - Email Records
    - Email: News; Zimbabwe, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Email: News: General/ Regional Multi, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Email: News: Zaire, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 112, 112a)
    - Email: News: Other Areas, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 113,114)
    - Email: News: Africa: Military, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Email: News: Africa: Other Pol, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 116)
    - Email: News Africa: Other Econ, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 117)
    - Email: News: Africa: Debt/WB/IMF, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Email: News: Africa: OAU, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Email: News: Africa: Trade/ Investment, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Email: News: Africa: UN, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - Email: News: Zambia, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 122-124)
    - Email News: Beijing, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 125-127)
    - Email: Incoming Correspondence, 1996 Jul-Dec (Box 12, Folder 128-129)
    - Email: Outgoing Correspondence, 1996 Jul-Dec (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - Email: News: Nigeria, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 131-133)
    - Email: News: Rwanda, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - Email: News: Southern Africa, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 135-136)
    - Email: News: Uganda, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Email: News: Sudan, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - Email: News: Angola, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 139-140)
    - Email: News: Burundi, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Email: News: Zaire, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 142-143)
    - Email: News: Liberia, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 144-145)
    - Email: News: Great Lakes ( Burundi, Rwanda, Tanzania, Uganda, Zaire), 1996 (Box 16, Folder 146-147)
    - Email: News: Kenya, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Email: News: Liberia, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Email: News: Liberia, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 150-152)
    - Email: News: Namibia, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 153)
    - Email: News: Mozambique, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 154)
    - Email: News: South Africa, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 155)
    - Email: News: Liberia, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 156-157)
- Country Files, Series II
  - Angola: Atrocities, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 158)
  - Algeria, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 159-160)
  - Angola, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 161-162)
  - Benin, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 163)
  - Burkina Faso, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 164)
  - Burundi, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 165-168)
  - Loose papers concerning Burundi (Box 20, Folder 169)
  - Burundi, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 170)
  - Cameroon, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 171)
  - Central Africa; general, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - Documents/ Publications (re. Central Africa ??), 1994 (Box 20, Folder 173)
  - Central Africa-general, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 174-175)
  - Central African Republic, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 176)
  - Congo- Brazzaville, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 177-180)
  - Democratic Republic of Congo, 1997 Jan-Feb (Box 20, Folder 181-184)
  - Democratic Republic Of Congo, 1997 Mar-May (Box 21, Folder 185-197)
  - Democratic Republic of Congo, 1997 Jun-Dec (Box 22, Folder 198-204)
  - East Africa; General, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 205-208)
  - East Africa-general, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 209)
  - Egypt, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 210-211)
  - Equatorial Guinea, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 212,212a)
  - Gabon, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 213)
  - Gambia, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 214)
  - Ghana, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 215)
  - Guinea Bissau, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 216)
  - Ivory Coast, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 217)
  - Kenya, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 218-220a)
  - Lesotho, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 221)
  - Liberia, 1995-1997 (Box 23, Folder 222-227)
  - Libya, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 228)
  - Malawi, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 229)
  - Mali, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 230)
  - Mauritania, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 231)
  - Mauritius, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 232)
  - Morocco, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 233)
  - Mozambique, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 234)
  - Namibia, 1988, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 235-236)
  - Niger, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Nigeria, 1996-1997 (Box 62, Folder 746-754)
  - Nigeria, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 238)
  - Nigeria: Washington Office on Africa Pack, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 239)
  - Nigeria Hill Drop, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 240)
  - Nigeria/ Irton, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 241,242)
  - Nigeria, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 243,244)
  - Nigeria, 1995-1997 (Box 24a, Folder 244a)
  - North Africa (Box 24a, Folder 244b)
  - Loose news magazines and newspapers concerning Nigeria, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 245)
  - Rwanda, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 246,247)
  - Documents/ Publications (re. Rwanda ??), 1994 (Box 25, Folder 248)
  - Rwanda, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 249)
  - Rwanda, 1995-1996 (Box 25, Folder 250,251)
  - Rwanda, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 252-252b)
  - Senegal, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 253)
  - Sierra Leone, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 254)
  - Somalia, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 255-255b)
  - Somalia (Box 26a, Folder 255c-255o)
  - Somalia (Box 26b, Folder 255p-255u)
  - South Africa (misc), 1992 (Box 26b, Folder 256)
  - South Africa (Box 27, Folder 257-259)
  - South Africa, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 260-261)
  - South Africa aid, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 262)
  - South Africa Culture, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 263)
  - South Africa Development, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 264)
  - South Africa Economy, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 265)
  - South Africa Health, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 266)
  - South Africa Human Rights, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 267)
  - South Africa Peacekeeping, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 268)
  - South Africa Politics, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 269a-g)
  - South Africa Trade and Trade Unions, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 270)
  - Southern Africa -general, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 271a-j)
  - South Africa -religion (Box 28, Folder 271k)
  - South Africa - women (Box 28, Folder 271L)
  - South Africa -sports (Box 28, Folder 271m)
  - Southern Africa, 1997 (Box 28a, Folder 272,272a)
  - Sudan, 1993-1997 (Box 28a, Folder 273-278)
  - Swaziland, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 279)
  - Tanzania, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 280)
  - Togo, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 281)
  - Tunisia, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 282)
  - Uganda, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 283)
  - Western Sahara, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 284)
  - West Africa -general, 1997 (Box 28b, Folder 285)
  - Zaire, 1992 (Box 28b, Folder 286)
  - Zaire, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 287)
  - Zaire Cohen Meeting, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - Zaire: Kansteiner Mtg., 1992 (Box 29, Folder 289)
  - Zaire: Legislation, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 290)
  - Zaire (misc) (Box 29, Folder 291)
  - Zaire, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 292-298)
  - Zaire, 1995-1997 (Box 29, Folder 298)
  - Zambia: economy, 1966-77 (Box 30, Folder 300)
  - Zambia; Trasp; TanZam; Copper; Power, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 301)
  - Zambia and WB and EX-IM BK Unaid and US official documents and China aid, 1973-1976 (Box 30, Folder 302)
  - Zambia, Rhodesia, and SA, 1971-1977 (Box 30, Folder 303)
  - Zambia, Ambassador of Republic of, 1970-71 (Box 30, Folder 304)
  - Zambia Politics, 1970-77 (Box 30, Folder 305)
  - Zambia, 1977-79, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 306-307)
  - Zimbabwe-Economy, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 308)
  - Zimbabwe; Economy; Exports; Tobacco; Dow, Lohnes and Albertson, Agents, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 309)
  - Zimbabwe; Military, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 310)
  - Zimbabwe; Military, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 311)
  - Zimbabwe; Politics, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 312)
  - Zimbabwe; Elections, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 313)
  - Zimbabwe; Political, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 314)
  - Zimbabwe, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 315)
- Topical Files, Series III
  - Religious
    - United Church of Christ, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 316)
    - Churches; 1990 thru 1994, 1990-1994 (Box 31, Folder 317)
    - Southern African Catholic Bishop Conference, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 318)
    - Churches, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 319,319a)
    - Church Women United, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 320)
    - Church World Service, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 321)
    - Religious Action Center of Reformed Judaism, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    - Lutheran World Info, 1990-1996 (Box 31, Folder 323)
    - Maryknoll Sisters and Brothers, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 324)
    - Presbyterian Church, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 325)
    - Religious: Organization, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 326)
    - United Church of Christ (Canada), 1993-1996 (Box 31, Folder 327)
    - Evangelicals for Social Action, 1990-1992 (Box 32, Folder 328)
    - NCC, 1994-1997 (Box 32, Folder 329)
    - Impact, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 330)
    - On Earth Peace Assembly, Inc, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 331)
    - Jesuit Refugee Service, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 332)
    - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1995-1997 (Box 32, Folder 333)
    - Episcopal Church, 1995-1997 (Box 32, Folder 334)
    - WCC, 1996-1999 (Box 32, Folder 335)
    - WISC, 1996-1998 (Box 32, Folder 336)
    - Religious Freedom Persecution, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 337)
    - Churches, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 338)
    - Interfaith Impact workshop Handouts: Nigeria Sanction Bill, 1997 Mar (Box 32, Folder 339)
    - CEDPA Interfaith Conference on Women, Poverty and Population, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 340,341)
    - Faith Action Group, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 342)
    - Church Groups Articles- general, 1990-1994 (Box 32, Folder 343)
    - Church of the Brethren, 1994-1997 (Box 32, Folder 344)
    - American Baptist Churches, 1991-1997 (Box 32, Folder 345)
    - Bread for the World, 1994-1997 (Box 32, Folder 346)
    - Center of Concern, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 347)
    - Catholic Inst. for International Relations, 1990-1993 (Box 32, Folder 348)
    - SACC, 1993-1997 (Box 33, Folder 349)
    - Africa Enterprise, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 350)
    - Comboni Missionaries, 1996-1997 (Box 33, Folder 351)
  - NGOs
    - US; Politics; NGOs African Grps Natl Task force on South Africa TUCC, 1972-1975 (Box 33, Folder 352)
    - US Politics; NGOs; Africa Grps. Natl Southern African Research Association, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 353)
    - Operation Namibia, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 354)
    - US; Politics: NGOs; Africa Grps. Natl American Committee on Africa, 1977-81 (Box 33, Folder 355)
    - US: Politics: NGOs: Africa Grps. Natl Southern Africa Media Center, 1977-1981 (Box 33, Folder 356,357)
    - US Politics; NGOs; Africa Grps. Natl SAMRAF/ COSAWR, 1978-1981 (Box 33, Folder 358)
    - US: Politics: NGOs: African Grps. Natl TRANSAFRICA, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 359)
    - Emergency Fund on Southern Africa, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 360)
    - US Politics: NGOs: Africa Grps. Episcopal Churchmen for the Southern Africa, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 361)
    - Southern Africa Support Project, 1979-1981 (Box 34, Folder 362)
    - US; Politics: NGOs: Africa Grps Natl Africare, 1979-1982 (Box 34, Folder 363)
    - X Catalyst Project, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 364)
    - US; Politics; NGOs; African Grps. Natl Southern Africa Working Groups, 1982-1984 (Box 34, Folder 365)
    - NGOs: American Friends Service Committee, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 366)
    - NGO; Diakonia South Africa, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 367)
    - NGO; Foundation For Contemporary Res South Africa, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 368)
    - NGO; Human Science Res Council S. Africa (Box 34, Folder 368a)
    - NGO; International Community Growth Fund, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 369)
    - NGO; Labour Law Unit, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 370)
    - NGO; International Planact, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 371)
    - International Contacts South Africa, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 372)
    - NGO; International ELTSA, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 373)
    - International NGOs, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 374,375)
    - NGO; Senegal Support Soc., INC Senegal, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 376)
    - NGO; Community Development Resource Assc. South Africa, 1993/1994 (Box 35, Folder 377)
    - Nordiska Africa Institute Annual Report, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 378)
    - NGO; Innova Securities, South Africa, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 379)
    - NGO; Africa M to Z, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 380)
    - NGO; NDM (Nigeria Democratic Movement) Nigeria, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 381)
    - NGO; Fix Freedom of Expression Institute of South Africa, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 382)
    - NGO; Program for Development Research Southern Africa, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 383)
    - NGO; African Center for Democracy and Human Rights Studies, Gambia, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 384)
    - NGO; One African, Centric Continental African Government NOW. Ghana, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 385)
    - Afronet, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 386)
    - NGO; Africa Institute on South Africa, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 387)
    - NGO; Inter Press Services (Global Agency News) Zimbabwe (Box 35, Folder 388)
    - NGOs: Religious, 1995-1996 (Box 35, Folder 389)
    - NGO; ZIBF Trust, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 390)
    - Miscellaneous papers concerning Human Rights Watch Arms Project, Zimbabwe, Rwanda, Zaire, Ken Saro-Wiwa, NCC-Washington Office, The Africa Fund, etc, 1978-1995 (Box 35, Folder 391,392)
    - NGOs general, 1990-96 (Box 35, Folder 393)
    - Mindolo Ecumenical Foundation (Box 36, Folder 393a)
    - Misc. Documents-NGOs (Box 36, Folder 394)
  - Trade
    - Trade and Investment In Africa, 1994-95 (Box 36, Folder 395)
    - Arms Trade and Control, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 396)
    - Trade; Reference; Enterprise Funds, 1994-96 (Box 36, Folder 397)
    - Trade; Reference; Export Processing Zones, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 398)
    - Trade; Reference Fast Track, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 399)
    - Trade; Food Security, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 400)
    - Trade; Reference; GATT, GSP,WTO, 1996-97 (Box 36, Folder 401)
    - Trade: Reference; MAI, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 402)
    - Trade Reference; Trade Initiatives and Stats, 1996-1997 (Box 36, Folder 403)
    - Trade; Reference; OPIC, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 404)
    - Overseas Private InvestmentCorporation (OPIC) (Box 36, Folder 405)
    - Trade; Reference; General Economic Policy, 1996-1997 (Box 36, Folder 406)
    - Notes, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 407)
    - Loose Papers concerning Trade (Box 37, Folder 408-412)
    - Trade; Trade Subcommittee Hearing (04/29/97), 1997 (Box 37, Folder 413,414)
    - Trade; Africa Subcommittee Hearing (05/21/97), 1997 (Box 37, Folder 415)
    - Trade; Africa Subcommittee Hearing (05/21/97), 1997 (Box 38, Folder 416)
    - Trade; Africa Growth and Opportunity Act, 1996-97 (Box 38, Folder 417-420)
    - Trade; Op-eds/ Articles in AGOA, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 421)
    - Trade; Senate Committee Hearing (07/31/97), 1997 (Box 38, Folder 422)
    - Trade; US Trade Rep. Policy and Executive Branch, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 423,424)
    - Arms Trade Code of Conduct, 1996-1997 (Box 38, Folder 425)
  - Advocacy Work and Topical Files
    - Women-general, 1970-83 (Box 38, Folder 426,427)
    - Misc. Mailing Lists, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 428,429)
    - Films on Southern Africa, 1974- (Box 39, Folder 430)
    - O Povo Organizado, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 431)
    - Soweto Slide Lists, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 432)
    - Publication Lists, Resources, 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 433)
    - Miscellaneous papers concerning Human Rights Watch Arms Project, Zimbabwe, Rwanda, Zaire, Ken Sarowiwa, NCC-Washington Office, The Africa Fund, etc, 1978-1995 (Box 39, Folder 434,435)
    - Film Resources California Newsreel, 1978-1981 (Box 39, Folder 436)
    - Maps- South Africa (Box 39, Folder 437)
    - Film Resources and Slide Tape, 1979-1982 (Box 40, Folder 438)
    - USAID-general information, 1981-1995 (Box 40, Folder 439)
    - Awake From Mourning, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 440)
    - D.C Divest Bill, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 441)
    - Women-general, 1984-1986 (Box 40, Folder 442)
    - Adam Megans Day- Resolution on, 1985-1986 (Box 40, Folder 443)
    - Aid-Gray Amend., 1986-1993 (Box 40, Folder 444)
    - Jonas Savimbi, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 445)
    - USAID and South Africa, 1987-92 (Box 40, Folder 446)
    - Women-general, 1987-88 (Box 40, Folder 447)
    - Angola Audio Visual Project, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 448)
    - Marcus Raskin, "Winning America" Institute for Policy Studies, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 449)
    - Africa- Non South African Info, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 450)
    - Conferences, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 451)
    - SADCC Handbook, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 452)
    - Carolina Interfaith Task Force on Central America, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 453)
    - Tutu Desmond, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 454)
    - Peace Development Fund, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 455)
    - Global Ministries, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 456)
    - Development Fund for Africa, 1988-1996 (Box 41, Folder 457)
    - Technical, 1988-1989 (Box 41, Folder 458)
    - ACAS Bulletin, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 459)
    - Bombing of South African Council of Churches, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 460)
    - ASALN-American South African Lawyers Alert, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 461)
    - ACOA, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 462)
    - Bills ( Legislative Matter) in Congress, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 463)
    - AFSC: Soviet -US seminar, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 464)
    - Unita and Angola, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 465)
    - Interim Correspondence-favorable and pending, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 466)
    - Nelson Mandela NRC-USA, 1990-93 (Box 41, Folder 467)
    - Documents/ Publications, 1990-1994 (Box 42, Folder 468-470)
    - Documents/ Publications (Box 42, Folder 471,472)
    - WOA TY 1992, 1991-1995 (Box 42, Folder 473)
    - African American Issues, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 474,475)
    - Bush Administration, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 476)
    - Clinton Administration, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 477)
    - Doug's Critique of AID-SA, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 478)
    - Policy Papers, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 479)
    - Folder entitled "original texts", 1993 (Box 43, Folder 480)
    - Congress/Legislation, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 481)
    - EMPSA Report, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 482)
    - Sources of Social Policy, 1993-95 (Box 43, Folder 483-489)
    - CBC International Affairs Brain Trust, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 490)
    - Red Folder containing misc. Documents (Box 44, Folder 491)
    - Project Files: House Africa Subcommittee, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 492)
    - Misc. Documents-Congress, Legislation, etc (Box 44, Folder 493)
    - Misc. Documents-WOA, Advocacy (Box 44, Folder 494)
    - SACC/WCC (misc) (Box 44, Folder 495)
    - GATT, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 496)
    - GATT and Africa (WNA), 1993-1995 (Box 44, Folder 497)
    - Congress/Legislation D93, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 498)
    - 103th Congress, 1993-94 (Box 44, Folder 499)
    - Legislation HR 2703; Mickey Leland Telecommunications and Education Act, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 500)
    - Legislation HR3334; Limitations of US armed forces, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 501)
    - Legislation HR 3690; Development assistance /NGOs and Government/democracy, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 502)
    - House Hearing: Foreign Aid Reform, 1993 Jul 26 (Box 45, Folder 503)
    - African American Issues, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 504-505)
    - African American Issues, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 506, 506a)
    - Shell/ Oil/ Environment/ Ogoni People, 1994-1997 (Box 45, Folder 507)
    - US Military Arms, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 508)